healthcaremagic.com 2019-03-27

# Privacy Policy - HealthcareMagic

**NOTICE OF PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA**

**WHO IS USING YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

**_HealthcareMagic_** , (' ** _HealthcareMagic_** ', ' **we** ', ' **us** ', ' **our** ') is one of the leading health portals allowing interaction between Doctors and Users (" **User** ") over Internet and phone.

In providing this service we will act as a 'processor' in relation to your personal data.

**SCOPE OF THIS NOTICE**

Please read this notice carefully. It applies to the treatment of any information that could be used to identify you as an individual and which is collected through your use or interaction with our website and services (" **personal data** "). The protection of your personal data is very important to us, and we understand our responsibilities to handle your personal data with care, to keep it secure and to comply with legal requirements.

This notice is not intended to override the terms of any contract that you or any relevant User may have with us, or that you may have with any relevant User, or any rights you might have available under applicable data protection laws.

We may make changes to this notice from time to time, for example to keep it up to date or to comply with legal requirements or changes in the way we operate our business.

We encourage you to regularly check back and review this policy so that you will always know what information we collect, how we use it, and who we share it with.

Do not disclose any personally identifiable information including, but not limited to, your name, email address, phone number, and date of birth in any section of the website, irrespective of whether you have paid for the service or not. The information you submit to HealthcareMagic may be used to help other users who are searching for information about similar health conditions. Any information that you submit to HealthcareMagic is searchable by search engines.

**WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT?**

We will process the personal data that you provide to us and/or the User, or any person acting on behalf of a User and/or which you record when using our software products and services, in particular your  ** _contact details_** , including your full name, job title, employment details including your employer, your business email address, and telephone number, your health problems, and records uploaded by you. In limited circumstances when you contact us for support, this might also include the limited details that you make available in relation to the issue.

We comply with the data minimization principles of data protection laws and we will not collect any personal data from you we do not need, in order to provide and oversee our services. In particular, we do not collect any special categories of data, in the general course of providing services in connection with our products or through making the Website available, unless required and only when we have an appropriate legal basis to do so.  ** **

**WHEN DO WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA?**

We will collect information from you  _directly_  when you use the Website. To the extent permitted by law, we may also monitor and record telephone calls for training and quality assurance purposes when you call the help desk  _directly_  for user support. Information about you may also be provided to us  _indirectly_  by a User.

**WHAT PURPOSE DO WE USE YOUR DATA FOR?**

We need to process your  ** _contact details  _**in order to operate our services. We would like to use this information to inform you of anything that may impact your ability to make use of the services. If you do not provide this information, it may result in us being unable to provide our contractual services.

We will collect your  ** _device data_**  to provide and operate our software products and the Website; to further develop, customize, and improve our software products and the Website based on visitors' and users' common or personal preferences, experiences, and difficulties; to provide ongoing customer assistance and technical support; to enhance our data security and fraud prevention capabilities and to comply with any applicable laws and regulations.

We have to establish a legal ground to use your personal data, so we will make sure that we only use your personal data for the purposes set out above where we are satisfied that:

  1. our use of your personal data is necessary to support 'Legitimate Interests' that we have as a business (namely, to improve our products or services, to provide help or support in connection with our products and the website, to ensure that our products and the website operate efficiently and securely, and to carry out analytics across our datasets), provided it is always carried out in a way that is proportionate, and that respects your privacy rights; and/or
  2. our use of your personal data is necessary to comply with a relevant legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to (e.g. to comply with FCA or ICO requirements).

Before collecting and/or using any special categories of data we will establish an additional lawful ground to those set out above which will allow us to use that information. This additional exemption will typically be:

  1. your explicit consent;
  2. the establishment, exercise or defence by us or third parties of legal claims; or
  3. a specific exemption provided under local laws of EU Member States and other countries implementing the GDPR.

**PLEASE NOTE**. If you provide your explicit consent to allow us to process your special categories of data, you may withdraw your consent to such processing at any time. However, you should be aware that if you choose to do so we may be unable to continue to provide certain services to you. If you choose to withdraw your consent we will tell you more about the possible consequences.

We will send emails to the email address you provide, and we will call the phone numbers you provide, if required. In case you have given a wrong email address or phone number for correspondence, HealthcareMagic is not responsible for any loss of information or privacy.

The information you submit to HealthcareMagic may be seen by service providers, such as doctors, or by operations and maintenance teams repairing and maintaining our technical systems. HealthcareMagic does not have Non-Disclosure Agreements with these parties, who may be able to access your information.

HealthcareMagic may use the information you submit to HealthcareMagic to study results and produce reports. Such information may be shared with HealthcareMagic partners and advertisers under the sole discretion of HealthcareMagic.

All details shared with us are only used to communicate with them or for addressing their specific queries and is never shared with any third party for the purposes of business promotion or marketing.

**WHERE IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA STORED?**

All the personal data we process is processed by our staff. For the purposes of IT hosting and maintenance of our website, this information is located on various servers hosted by our data center providers across different locations. We will not share your personal data outside the European Union unless it is a transfer to a country which is recognized as providing an adequate level of legal protection or by ensuring that transfers are protected by contractual commitments for additional security - for example, the EU - U.S. Privacy Shield for the protection of personal data transferred to the US. In those cases you will have the right to ask us for more information about the safeguards we have put in place as mentioned above (e.g. to request a copy where the safeguard is documented, which may be redacted to ensure confidentiality).

No third parties, other than those that you chose to transact with over our products and services, have access to your personal data unless authorised by law, for example a regulatory body. We take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal data is processed securely.

**HOW LONG DO WE KEEP IT?**

In relation to your  ** _contact details_** ,we will retain your data for so long as is instructed by the relevant controller. In some circumstances we may retain your personal data for longer periods of time, for example where we are required to do so to meet legal, regulatory, tax, or accounting requirements, in particular where it forms part of an audit trail created to record your use of our website.

For the  ** _device data_**  we will retain your personal data for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes listed in this notice, and in line with our cookie settings for example.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges, or if we reasonably believe there is a possibility of legal action relating to your personal data or dealings.

HealthcareMagic uses Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online.

Third-party vendors, including Google, show HealthcareMagic's ads on sites across the Internet. HealthcareMagic and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and deliver ads based on someone's past visits to our website.

HealthcareMagic's websites contain links to other sites. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website collecting personal information.

**WHAT ARE YOUR RIGHTS?**

You have a number of rights in relation to your personal data which should be exercised by contacting the  **HealthcareMagic**  who is the 'controller' of this data. In summary, you may request us to ensure you can access your data, request the rectification of any mistakes relating to your data, request the erasure of records which are no longer required, request the restriction on the processing of your data, object to the processing of your data, or request to exercise your right of data portability. You also have various rights in relation to any automated decision making and profiling, however we do not carry out these activities in connection with our products or services.

**CONTACT AND COMPLAINTS**

You can contact us with any queries or concerns at the following email address [GDPR.adam@ebix.com](mailto:GDPR.adam@ebix.com)

If you have a complaint or concern about how we use your personal data, please contact us in the first instance and we will attempt to resolve the issue as soon as possible. You also have a right to lodge a complaint with your national data protection supervisory authority at any time. In the UK, the supervisory authority for data protection is the ICO (<https://ico.org.uk/)>. We do ask that you please attempt to resolve any issues with us first, although you have a right to contact your supervisory authority at any time.
